Class of 1953 Records, 1949-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Class of 1953 Records
1949-[ongoing]
Smith College. Class of 1953.
RG 80 UUID:860b6c22-2f66-464b-ba93-ba2968121b44
8 boxes (5 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1953.
The Class of 1953 was the seventy-fifth graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1953 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1953, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, extensive correspondences, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1953 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Alumnae Association-General 1978 (Box 2188, Folder 1)
- Alumnae Funds 1967-1968 (Box 2188, Folder 2)
- Alumnae Funds 1969-1976 (Box 2188, Folder 3)
- Alumnae Funds 1977-1978 (Box 2188, Folder 4)
- Alumnae Funds 1981-1993 (Box 2188, Folder 5)
- Alumnae Leadership on Council 1988-1989 (Box 2188, Folder 6)
- Alumnae Leadership on Council 1989-1990 (Box 2188, Folder 7)
- Alumnae Leadership on Council 1990-1991 (Box 2188, Folder 8)
- Alumnae Leadership on Council 1992-1993 (Box 2188, Folder 9)
- Class Baby 1992 (Box 2188, Folder 10)
- Class Bequest Program 1975-1991 (Box 2188, Folder 11)
- Bylaws undated (Box 2188, Folder 12)
- Commencement 1953 (Box 2188, Folder 13)
- Commencement-Dramatics 1953 (Box 2188, Folder 14)
- Commencement-Photographs 1953 (Box 2188, Folder 15)
- Commencement-Speaker 1953 (Box 2188, Folder 16)
- Convocation 1949 (Box 2188, Folder 17)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Association 1953-1959 (Box 2188, Folder 18)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Association 1960-1969 (Box 2188, Folder 19)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Association 1970-1979 (Box 2188, Folder 20)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Association 1987-1988 (Box 2188, Folder 21)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Association 1992-1993 (Box 2188, Folder 22)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1953-1960 (Box 2188, Folder 23)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1961-1962 (Box 2188, Folder 24)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1963-1967 (Box 2188, Folder 25)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1968-1969 (Box 2188, Folder 26)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1970-1976 (Box 2188, Folder 27)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1977-1979 (Box 2188, Folder 28)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1980-1981 (Box 2188, Folder 29)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1982-1983 (Box 2188, Folder 30)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1984-1985 (Box 2188, Folder 31)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1987-1988 (Box 2188, Folder 32)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1988-1989 (Box 2188, Folder 33)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1990-1991 (Box 2188, Folder 34)
- Correspondence-Alumnae Funds 1992-1993 (Box 2188, Folder 35)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1953-1963 (Box 2189, Folder 1)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1966-1967 (Box 2189, Folder 2)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1968-1969 (Box 2189, Folder 3)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1970-1971 (Box 2189, Folder 4)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1972-1976 (Box 2189, Folder 5)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1977-1978 (Box 2189, Folder 6)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1979-1980 (Box 2189, Folder 7)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1981-1982 (Box 2189, Folder 8)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1983-1984 (Box 2189, Folder 9)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1987-1988 (Box 2189, Folder 10)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1988-1989 (Box 2189, Folder 11)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1989-1990 (Box 2189, Folder 12)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1990-1991 (Box 2189, Folder 13)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1991-1992 (Box 2189, Folder 14)
- Correspondence-Class Officers 1993-1994 (Box 2189, Folder 15)
- Correspondence-Racial Issues at Smith 1988 (Box 2189, Folder 16)
- Daughters of Smith Alums Enrolled at Smith undated (Box 2189, Folder 17)
- Employment Status 1953 (Box 2189, Folder 18)
- Freshman Handbook 1949-1950 (Box 2189, Folder 19)
- General 1952 (Box 2189, Folder 20)
- Groups 1949-1953, 1991-1992 (Box 2189, Folder 21)
- History 1949-1953 (Box 2189, Folder 22)
- Hoop Rolling 1953 (Box 2189, Folder 23)
- House Representatives 1977-1982 (Box 2189, Folder 24)
- Ivy Day 1953 (Box 2189, Folder 25)
- Junior Ushers 1952 (Box 2189, Folder 26)
- Class Letters 1953-1959 (Box 2189, Folder 27)
- Class Letters 1960-1969 (Box 2189, Folder 28)
- Class Letters 1970-1979 (Box 2189, Folder 29)
- Class Letters 1980-1989 (Box 2189, Folder 30)
- Class Letters 1990-2003 (Box 2189, Folder 31)
- Class Officers 1950 (Box 2189, Folder 32)
- Class Officers-Minutes undated (Box 2189, Folder 33)
- Organization (Box 2189, Folder 34)
  See Class of 1949 Organization
- Photographs undated (Box 2189, Folder 35)
- Scholarships and Student Aid 1966-1967 (Box 2189, Folder 36)
- Smith Club Associations 1967 (Box 2189, Folder 37)
- Songs undated (Box 2189, Folder 38)
- Sophomore Carnival 1951 (Box 2189, Folder 39)
- Step Sings 1953 (Box 2189, Folder 40)
- Treasurer's Report 1968-1992 (Box 2189, Folder 41)
- Who's Who 1949 (Box 2189, Folder 42)
- Reunions 1954 (Box 2191, Folder 1)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1954 (Box 2191, Folder 2)
- Reunions 1958 (Box 2191, Folder 3)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1958 (Box 2191, Folder 4)
- Reunions 1963 (Box 2191, Folder 5)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1963 (Box 2191, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1968 (Box 2191, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1968 (Box 2191, Folder 8)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1968 (Box 2191, Folder 9)
- Reunions-Commencement Parade Correspondence 1968 (Box 2191, Folder 10)
- Reunions 1973 (Box 2191, Folder 11)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1973 (Box 2191, Folder 12)
- Reunions 1978 (Box 2191, Folder 13)
- Reunions 1978 (Box 2191, Folder 14)
- Reunions 1978 (Box 2191, Folder 15)
- Reunions-Geneva Group 1978 (Box 2191, Folder 16)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1982-1983 (Box 2192, Folder 1)
- Reunions 1983 (Box 2192, Folder 2)
- Reunions 1983 (Box 2192, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1988 (Box 2192, Folder 4)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1987-1988 (Box 2192, Folder 5)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1991-1992 (Box 2192, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1993 (Box 2192, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1998 (Box 2192, Folder 8)
- Reunions-Correspondence 1995-2001 (Box 2192, Folder 9)
- Reunions-50th 2003 (Box 2192.1, Folder 1)
- Reunion Book 2003 (Box 2192.1, Folder 2)